# **DEEPAK KUMAR**

**Profile** 

(+91) 9199406321, (+91) 8052211414 dk66186@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY:**

**Full Stack Developer** with over 3.5 years of IT experience. Versatile, bilingual professional with projects ranging in size from open source projects to full scale multi-million dollar high profile corporate construction projects. Ability to provide efficient solutions to real life problems and develop restful web services for operational intelligence. Currently working as **owner** of Ola Corporate from development side.

### **SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE:**

Ola Cabs 11/2017 – Present

Software Development Engineer (1 year 8 months)

Wipro Technologies Ltd. 07/2015 – 10/2017

Project Engineer (2 years 4 months)

### **EDUCATION:**

### Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi

2011-2015

B. Tech in Electrical Engineering (Cumulative CGPA: 8.09 on absolute scale)

### **SKILLS AND INTERESTS:**

- Technical Skills: Java, JavaScript, Node.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Spring MVC, Microservices
- Familiar Technologies: HTML, HTML5, CSS, D3.js, Bootstrap, Ruby, Python scripts
- Databases: SQL, Mongo DB
- · Areas of Interest: Data Structure and Algorithms. HLD, LLD, Design Patterns
- Tools used: Intellij Idea, Atom, Sublime Text, Sequel Pro

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE:**

**Project 1:** Currently working as **owner** for end to end application development of Ola Corporate.

[Team Size: 7] 11/2017 – current

- Responsible for development of various features from scratch (both frontend and backend part)
  mainly being user reports, groups and employee management and dashboard bookings.
- Was part of development of different dashboards based on user roles super and sales admin, manager approval and one travel desk.
- API's for third party integration for corporates to integrate with their own existing system.
- Scaled the corporate system from handing 10K rides per day to 30K per day and similarly we have more than 3000 B2B corporates for which we do automatic invoice generation monthly. Had significant contribution in developing and stabilization of invoice workflow which is our main source of revenue (Approx. 57-60 crores per month)
- Single handily managing corporate rides (B2B, B2C) from pre booking to closure along with building a robust corporate communications network.
- Was responsible for scaling the corporate system to handle traffic from both dashboard and app bookings.
- Part of design of ola corporate architecture along with upcoming corporate international features.
- Currently leading the team on internationalization of Ola Corporate in Australia, New Zealand and UK.
- Technologies Used: Java, Angular, JavaScript, Ruby, MySql, Microservices, Redis, Hazelcast cache, Elastic Search, Kafka, SQS, Rabbit MQ, dropwizard

Project 2: Developed full featured UI of Chatbot of Wipro HOLMES using meteor.is framework.

[Team Size: 6] 06/2017 – 10/2017

Project 3: Developed complete UI of a cognitive AI tool for a US title insurance company as part of client project.

[Team Size: 10] 11/2016 – 05/2017

• The UI has feature of both folder and file uploading along with save and update option for finding final vesting. It has a beautiful timeline feature along with various d3 graphs and table visualizations.

Project 4: Developed a tool for client that takes pdf, word, rtf documents as input and generates structured XML

[Team Size: 6] 07/2015 – 10/2016

- The tool extracts **entities** like front matter, paragraph, subparagraph, headers, footnotes etc. from unstructured data (pdf, word) and then fill them in their respective tags in **xml** format.
- Enhanced Apache pdf2html API **source code** to read bold, italic and underline information as well as to **annotate** entities in document itself.

Project 5: Developed a Chat Application that allows users to share text messages, photos, smileys and chat in groups. [Team Size: 2] 05/2017 – 06/2017

# **ACHIEVEMENTS / EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:**

- Did Immersive Full MEAN Stack Training in Stack route (NIIT CENTRE), Bangalore as a part of Wipro Digital Academy Training Program.
- Participation in ALL INDIA PAPER PRESENTATION CONTEST in first year (2011).
- Received scholarship for class 11th and 12th from school.
- Received a cash award of Rs 20,000 from Bihar state govt for securing 95% marks in class 10.
- Received 'Pratibha Samman' award from SBI Patna in 2011
- Github: https://github.com/deepak1745
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepak-kumar-9735396b